英会話タイムトライアル
Let's get started with the fourth day of our special week.
It's day 19 for the month of September.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sarese.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
今日は特別なチャレンジです。こちら。
Reply Around the Globe.
Tell me about some good or bad food that you've had recently.
最近食べた中で、美味しかった、もしくはまずかった食べ物について教えてください。
Today, we'll introduce the replies from three different people.
まず一人目です。
The first person we'll introduce is Zoe.
She's from Hawaii.
ハワイ出身のゾイさん、どのように答えてくるのか、早速聞いてみましょう。
Tell me about some good...
or bad food that you've had recently.
I ate a homemade pizza that had mozzarella,
and it was perfectly cooked.
It was not overcooked or undercooked.
Ooh, homemade pizza is always the best kind of pizza, isn't it, Steve?
Yes, if it's cooked perfectly.
Did you hear that?
It might have been a little too early.
Let's check the content.
Jenny, can you read Zoe's reply?
Sure, Steve.
I ate a homemade pizza that had mozzarella.
モッツァレラチーズを乗せた自家製ピザを食べました。
モッツァレラチーズを乗せたという表現は簡単に
that had mozzarella.
最後にon itがなくても表現できます。
And it was perfectly cooked.
It was not overcooked or undercooked.
完璧な焼き加減で 焼きすぎでも生焼けでもありませんでした
完璧な焼き加減 Perfectly cooked
さあ もう一度 ゾイさんのリプライをチェックしましょう
OK Now let's check out Zoe's reply one more time
Listen closely
I ate a homemade pizza that had mozzarella
And it was perfectly cooked
It was not overcooked or undercooked
The second person we'll introduce is Dean. He's from Australia.
Tell me about some good or bad food that you've had recently.
I went to a Greek restaurant for lunch the other day.
And I had the most amazing roast lamb.
And it was the best lunch I've had for as long as I can remember.
聞き取れましたか?
そんなに難しい単語は使ってないですね。
では、内容を確認しましょう。
I went to a Greek restaurant for lunch the other day.
先日、昼食でギリシャ料理のレストランに行きました。
The other day. これは便利な表現です。
日本語で言う先日。
いつなのか曖昧です。
だから便利です。
And I had the most amazing roast lamb.
最高のローストラムを食べました。
And it was the best lunch I've had for as long as I can remember.
覚えている限りで一番の昼食でした。
Deanさんは答えるのにZoeさんと同じように三つの文を言ってくれました。
それがしっかりしたリプライです。
基本は文を連続してリプライすることです。
では、もう一度ディーンさんのリプライをチェックしましょう。
Listen closely.
I went to a Greek restaurant for lunch the other day,
and I had the most amazing roast lamb,
and it was the best lunch I've had for as long as I can remember.
OK, now we'll introduce our last person, Dan from Ohio.
最後に登場するのは、オハイオ州出身のダンさんです。
Let's check it out.
Tell me about some good or bad food that you've had recently.
My mother-in-law made a key lime pie recently that was delicious, one of the best I've had.
And my wife loves liver and onions.
She made it for me, and I thought it was not very good.
Key lime pie, do you know what it is?
This is actually a dessert from Florida, where I'm from.
It's similar to a rare cheesecake, but it's a pie made with lime juice.
さあ、そんなキーライムパイ、そしてあんまりおいしくなかった料理についてもリプライしてくれましたね。内容をチェックしましょう。
My mother-in-law made a key lime pie recently.
最近、義理の母がキーライムパイを作りました。
That was delicious. One of the best I've had.
とてもおいしくて、これまで食べた中で最高のものでした。
And my wife loves liver and onions.
She made it for me.
また妻はレバーと玉ねぎの炒め物が大好きで、
それを私に作ってくれました。
And I thought it was not very good.
あんまりおいしいとは思いませんでした。
Good っていうのはおいしい。
Not very good っていうのはあんまりおいしくない。
Delicious を否定文にあんまり使わないです。
つまり、I thought it wasn't deliciousではなくて、ダンさんのように、I thought it was not very good。
それでは、もう一度、ダンさんのリプライをチェックしましょう。
Listen closely.
My mother-in-law made a key lime pie recently that was delicious, one of the best I've had.
And my wife loves liver and onions.
She made it for me, and I thought it was not very good.
さあ、次はあなたの番です。
Just try to reply and make as many sentences as you can in your own words.
Got it?
Okay, here's the question.
Tell me about some good or bad food that you've had recently.
Ready? Start.
Okay, time's up. How did you do? Did you make a few sentences in your own words?
それでは、ジェニーさんにも同じ質問に答えてもらいましょう。
Are you ready, Jenny?
I'm ready, Steve.
Tell everyone about some good or bad food that you've had recently. Start.
I recently went to an Italian restaurant in my neighborhood.
i had never been there before but i had the most delicious pizza i've ever had in my life steve
wow was it some kind of special pizza i'm not sure if it was the toppings or the bread
but the combination was just perfection all right i'm getting hungry
さあ、それでは皆さん、最後に、せっかくですからもう一度挑戦してみてください。
スムーズなリプライできるように頑張ってください。
OK, here's the question.
Tell me about some good or bad food that you've had recently.
All right. Great job, everyone.
さて、明日は英語の名曲をジェニーさんと一緒に歌ってみるコーナー。
What's this song?
So let's finish up this month singing together.
お楽しみに。
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
英会話タイムトライアル。
Bye-bye.